Yiming Gu (Samuel)

samuelgu_nuaa@yahoo.com

0435 842 801

Mest End, QLD, 4101

https://samuelgunuaa.gthub.io/

Personal Statement

For the past 8 months, I have been actively exploring the opportunity of being an IT engineer due to my new start of living in Brisbane.

I worked as a software engineer in ASUS for 10 years and then turned to be program manager in NXP and AMD in China. As a result, I have experiences on software development, Agile project management, troubleshooting and customer service. Now to be a qualified Frontend / Fullstack developer, I attended IT training courses to improve my skills to fit the future job. Learning new technology is always a difficult process, but I am a quick learner and like facing challenges, just like I successfully switched from a software engineer to a semiconductor program manager in a short time by quick learning 3 years ago.

I am an enthusiastic person and enjoy the opportunity to work both independently and with others. I am at my best when working in IT industry to expand my skills through my work experience to date.

Key Skills and Abilities

Coding Skills:

HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, React.js, ES6, C#, ASP.NET, C, Assembly

Management Skills:

Agile, Scrum, Jira, Git, Bitbucket, SVN, Project, Sharepoint

Other Skills:

Customer issue service
Hardware setup & troubleshooting
Program management

Employment History

June 2016 - March 2017 **Program Manager**

Advanced Micro Devices (Shanghai) Co., Ltd. Suzhou Branch



Responsibilities:

- > Defined VGA ASIC development milestones from product bring-up, sample validation to mass production.
- Agile testing program developing life-cycle management by Jira, Sharepoint.
- Worked with core team to achieve milestones and commit delivery schedules.
- Defined engineering services, manage engineering priorities and resources.
- Lessons learned presentation.

October 2015 - May 2016 **Software Program Manager**

Freescale Semiconductor (Shanghai) Co., Ltd. (Merged to NXP)



Responsibilities:

- Led technical product design review and program execution on Freescale MPU chipsets.
- ➤ Made and controlled budget for software team's development.
- Planned and tracked software development schedule, risk report, revision release by MS Project, Sharepoint, Git, Jira.
- Held software team meeting as Agile development methodology.
- Addended PMO regular meeting for project report.
- Participated in reviewing marketing requirements document to ensure the scope, schedule and cost were reasonable and achievable.

July 2005 - May 2015 **System Engineer** ASUS Technology (Suzhou) Co., Ltd.



Responsibilities:

- Discussed ASUS motherboard specification, technical features, risks and schedule with core team.
- Established and maintained project design documents to ensure all features were matched.
- Developed software for Intel desktop and mobile products by C and Assembly.
- > Created test plans, established test system with QA team for function validation.
- Software development, validation and release in Agile.
- ➤ Worldwide customer and vendor issue service with quick solutions.

Education

Frontend / Fullstack Developer Training Jiangren Brisbane March 2018 -

Bachelor of Computer Science and Technology Nanjing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics

Nanjing, China

Graduated: 2005

References

AMD:

Hock-Leong Ong Senior Product Manager

E: Hock-Leong.Ong@amd.com

T: 65-6796 9411

FSL/NXP:

Kenny Xu General Manager

E: Xiangfa.Xu@nxp.com

T: 86-21-2893721 M: 86-139 1891 2368

ASUS:

Anny Wei BIOS Director

E: Anny_Wei@asus.com T: 86-512-66613887-47301

M: 86-139 1314 0334